Hi, I'm Snow from team four lemurs and
we have built open haven. This is where
you hire AI co-workers for a team. They
live with a team handle lot of brunt
work 24/7.
Typically such AI agents don't build a
context. They don't adapt with you. Open
human overcomes this problem with the
power of co's memory layer. So these AI
co-workers, they remember everything you
want them to and they even build
connections over time. Uh here's the
team. We have experts for practically
every domain. For instance, if you hire
the support worker, she can respond to
queries on your Discord support channel
or respond to emails. And because she
remembers your company's policy and past
incidents, she can take up most of such
issues.
On boarding them is pretty easy tasks.
You just feed them what you want them to
know and you invite them to your Slack
or Discord or whatever you use and you
give them their duties. That's it. And
they get to work.
Each of them has their own set of
responsibilities and tools to help them
carry out their job. For example, for
the uh engineer coworker, you can
connect them to your GitHub or Versel or
practically any development tool you use
and they can help you with them to
answer something like did that bug get
fixed or uh to to raise a PR
and because they have their own
independent memories and they can
collaborate with them, they practically
act like your team.
So this is the overall architecture of
our project. The dashboard where you
might run and control most of the things
like agents, memory system and MCP
servers. The memory layer powered by
Cogni's open source system.
Every AI coworker that you hire has its
own specific memory, its own data set
that only it can write into. But they
can read the company by database.
The agents or AI co-workers as we call
them.
They interact with you via Slack or
Discord or even ClickUp. And they all
use various MCP tools to actually do
their work.
We have notion, GitHub and many more.
Depending on what what type of work that
AI worker has, you can choose any of
them and make your own combinations.
So this is how we manage our AI workers.
Alison and Marcus have been on board for
quite some time. Let's take a look at
the HR specialist. It's connected to
Slack and is active and has a duty of
answering employee HR questions using
company policies and past conversations
already in its memory. An escalating
request that require approval.
and Marcus
the sales representative is also
connected
and has the GA presentation MCP for
creating pitch decks that are required
in sales.
Let's onboard the customer support
coworker Alex.
We just need to give the DT to track any
updates in company policy and help the
co-workers with them. And then we just
add
what it needs to know to start working.
It can be the company. It can be the
company policies, handbooks,
documentation. And it's not limited to a
particular file type. You can upload
PDFs, words, excels, even markdowns or
in fact even uh website URLs because
Cognney uh inherently supports all of
these file types out of the box.
And now we just connect to the Slack
Slack channel
and add it to the workspace. And that's
it.
Now it's live a part of our team.
Now Alex is also a part of our team. If
I want any of my AI co-workers to
remember or forget something, I can just
drop them a text. Like if I want to
update some particular thing and then
Alex remember that from now we don't
sell it companies.
Now in the back end my mess will trigger
companies methods like dot remember or
forget. So these update the memories of
that specific uh corker that I'm tagging
and besides explicitly them to remember
something we can also use u reactions
like if I uh react thumbs up to this
particular message
then to use cogni improve function to
reinforce the idea that this particular
piece of information is extra important.
So it gets highlighted in the graph and
if I react thumbs down then gets uh
either dropped or it's marked of less
importance. Now if I want to apply for a
leave,
Alison is the HI employee. So I ask her,
I want to apply.
Now inside her brain, inside her memory,
Alice knows the company's leave policy
and as well as my attendance record. So
she uses both of them to come up with a
decision and take actions based on that.
Alison's reply.
So because I've already reached my PTO
status, I have used my annual cap has
reached. I have used both of my uh
previews already. Uh this has been
escalated to a human supervisor.
In such cases that Alison cannot handle
herself, she escalates these messages to
a supervisor.
If another one of my teammate asks for a
lead instead of me and it's not just
limited to answering questions with a
memory, they can even take actions. I
have asked Marcus the saleserson
uh to to create a pitch tech
using yesterday's uh
yesterday's
meeting transcripts.
Max already knows what happened in
yesterday's meeting because uh he had
because he remembers the transcripts. So
you can extract features and uh
discussions we had using that and create
a pitch deck from it.
So our pitch de is ready.
Mark has extracted the meeting product
planning meetings transcripts which have
four of us as participants and it's a 11
slide deck.
This is what happens when memory needs
actual action because of the MCP tools
that they're using. And in a company
setting like this, such uh such AI
co-workers can be a great asset. And
this is the memory behind the scenes to
keep all employees transparent about
what they know uh what they have learned
and what connections they have made
between uh documents, concepts and even
entities. We can check out this
knowledge graph, interactive knowledge
graph on each employees detail page
which is provided by Cognney.
This is Alison's graph and in her memory
we can see what connections she has
built between different concepts. If you
want to look for a particular node like
if I want to know what she's what she
knows about the leave policy, I can just
search for it and and check out the
connections myself.
And the best part is that in the memory
there's a
you can see previous versions of it like
at what time at what specific time she
built some specific connections.
So you can backtrack it
and this is how the memory gets built
over time. In fixed durations all the
chat messages get ingested and there's a
small model which judges which of those
messages to send to the specific
employees. those employees uh ingest the
data in their own personal data sets and
if it triggers a task then they execute
it. As for the rest of the messages the
the globally important ones get saved in
the company data set and the rest of the
uh trash gets discarded
and behind the brains of these AI
co-workers is Cognney's memory layer.
Every time you create an organization,
you create an isolated company database
and inside it is the company's common
data set. And each time you onboard an
employee, they get their own data set as
well.
So employees can write only in their own
memories, but they can read uh all of
these data sets uh only when it's
needed. For example, uh if you ask,
"Hey, Alex, can you create a pipe from
last night's meeting?" Emily has a
dinosaur then Alex will be able to
access Emily's data set because the
breed permission is there but only needs
to be triggered by a particular command.
This keeps responsibility separate while
still letting everyone share company
context.
So that was open. You hire actual AI
co-workers that adapt to your company's
needs instead of chat bots. They live
wherever your team already works. They
remember your company's history and
actually make connections between your
conversations and documents. And they
don't just answer questions, they can
actually get work done. Thank you for
watching.